<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<resume>
	<section display="true">
		<title>Summary</title>
		<text>Over 10 years of progressive, comprehensive experience as an innovative web developing professional. A distinguished worker acknowledged for positive rapport among co-workers and clients. Detail oriented, with a proven ability to successfully contribute to company objectives. Well balanced workload of projects and tight deadlines in a fast paced environment. Aspiring to enhance skill set from cutting-edge technologies utilizing HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.</text>
	</section>
	<section display="true">
		<title>Professional Experience</title>
		<job>
			<company>Time Inc.</company>
			<city>New York, NY</city>
			<role>
				<name>Front-End Developer / Consumer Marketing + Revenue</name>
				<duration>2012 - Present</duration>
				<summary></summary>
				<item>Coordinated with QA testers for end-to-end unit testing and post-production testing. </item>
				<item>Supervised the work of 2 other front-end developers. </item>
				<item>Updated, modified and expanded existing iOS web applications. </item>
				<item>Trained 3 equipment operators, data entry and user personnel. </item>
				<item>Developed web applications for Apple iPad/iPhone and Kindle Fire platforms. </item>
				<item>Developed Time For Kids Classroom application with student / teacher web views and classroom assessments. </item>
				<item>Developed a responsive jQuery mini magazine web-based reader for marketing to replace a minimally supported Adobe Flash reader. </item>
				<item>Provided technical and development support to marketing JavaScript advertisements used across all Time Inc. brands. </item>
				<item>Implemented a custom filter to determine special issues from weekly / monthly issues not native to the Adobe DPS APIs. </item>
				<item>Produced reusable Omniture code to deliver descriptive user actions and page views for readable and effective reporting in SiteCatalyst. </item>
				<item>Managed and perfected special messaging to end-users during the release of iOS8 to keep app ratings substantial and customer service complaints minimal. </item>
				<item>Implemented A/B testing, manipulating DOM elements using local storage. </item>
				<item>Setup an automated posting script to pass data to the back-end for used for delivering audience segmented push notifications called ECHO. </item>
				<item>Transitioned Woodwing applications on iPad into a highly configurable Backbone application utilizing the latest Adobe DPS JavaScript APIs. </item>
			</role>
		</job>
		<job>
			<company>New York Post</company>
			<city>New York, NY</city>
			<role>
				<name>Web Developer / Online Production</name>
				<duration>2010 - 2012</duration>
				<summary></summary>
				<item>Planned and executed changes to both iPhone and Android mobile applications. </item>
				<item>Troubleshooted and resolved web application issues escalated from customer support and other departments with a 100% success rate. </item>
				<item>Built internal web tools for ad placement within mobile applications. </item>
				<item>Created HTML email templates and newsletters for e-mail marketing campaigns. </item>
				<item>Executed and monitored standards for user interfaces, page design and graphics development. </item>
				<item>Compiled statistical information for special reports. (Omniture / Chartbeat / Newsbeat) </item>
				<item>Designed templates for the CMS to promote SEO and conversion best practices and the efficient use of HTML tags. </item>
				<item>Managed all social media programs, including Internet forums, blogs, social networking applications and message boards. </item>
			</role>
		</job>
		<job>
			<company>Acxiom Digital</company>
			<city>New York, NY</city>
			<role>
				<name>Content Specialist Lead / Solutions Developer</name>
				<duration>2005 - 2010</duration>
				<summary></summary>
				<item>Designed dynamic microsites for start-up clients and multi-national corporations. </item>
				<item>Produced engaging email marketing campaigns with user segmentation and personalization. </item>
				<item>Accomplished in optimizing graphics and web-safe colors for fast download time. </item>
				<item>Produced high quality work with recognition of 12+ months error-free and close attention to detail. </item>
				<item>Implemented a JavaScript search API for a leading hotel chain. </item>
				<item>Created support documentation for web and data projects. </item>
				<item>Automated a B2B solution using Oracle PL/SQL stored procedures to subscribe and unsubscribe ~5K member per day. </item>
				<item>Developed an ASP API to subscribe new members based off a preference center submission and triggering an automated confirmation email. </item>
			</role>
		</job>
		<job>
			<company>Linium</company>
			<city>Albany, NY</city>
			<role>
				<name>Service Desk Support Professional</name>
				<duration>2004 - 2005</duration>
				<summary></summary>
				<item>Demonstrated effective and consistent technical support. </item>
				<item>Implemented procedures which provided the tools to automate a testing process. </item>
				<item>Performed troubleshooting of computer systems and related equipment. </item>
			</role>
		</job>
		<job>
			<company>Colgate University</company>
			<city>Hamilton, NY</city>
			<role>
				<name>Desktop Support Team (Internship)</name>
				<duration>2004</duration>
				<summary></summary>
				<item>Provided base level technical support to faculty, staff, and students. </item>
			</role>
		</job>
	</section>
	<section display="true">
		<title>Education</title>
		<college>
			<name>Morrisville State College</name>
			<city>Morrisville, NY</city>
			<degree>
				<type>B.Tech, Information Technology</type>
				<focus>Web Development</focus>
				<year>2004</year>
			</degree>
			<degree>
				<type>A.A.S., Computer Information Systems</type>
				<focus></focus>
				<year>2001</year>
			</degree>
		</college>
	</section>
	<section display="true">
		<title>Core Qualifications</title>
		<type>
			<name>&nbsp;</name>
			<skill>Adobe DPS APIs (JavaScript SDKs)</skill>
			<skill>Ajax</skill>
			<skill>Backbone.js</skill>
			<skill>Charles</skill>
			<skill>Chartbeat / Newsbeat</skill>
			<skill>CSS3</skill>
			<skill>Dropbox</skill>
			<skill>Google Analytics</skill>
			<skill>Fiddler</skill>
			<skill>Firebug</skill>
			<skill>Handlebars</skill>
			<skill>HTML5</skill>
			<skill>JavaScript</skill>
			<skill>JSON</skill>
			<skill>jQuery</skill>
			<skill>Methode (CMS)</skill>
			<skill>MySQL</skill>
			<skill>Oracle SQL</skill>
			<skill>Perl</skill>
			<skill>Photoshop</skill>
			<skill>PHP5</skill>
			<skill>PostgreSQL</skill>
			<skill>SASS / SCSS</skill>
			<skill>SailThru (ESP)</skill>
			<skill>SiteCatalyst</skill>
			<skill>Underscore.js</skill>
			<skill>VBScript</skill>
			<skill>XML</skill>
		</type>
	</section>
	<section display="true">
		<title>Additional Information</title>
		<job>
			<name>Github</name>
			<duration>&nbsp;</duration>
			<summary><a href="http://www.github.com/tkrofecheck">http://www.github.com/tkrofecheck</a></summary>
		</job>
		<job>
			<name>LinkedIn</name>
			<duration>&nbsp;</duration>
			<summary><a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/tkrofecheck">http://www.linkedin.com/in/tkrofecheck</a></summary>
		</job>
	</section>
	<section display="false">
		<title>Resume</title>
		<name>Download Hardcopy Resume</name>
		<url>https://www.dropbox.com/s/cthp6aa4uso0nes/TimKrofecheck_Resume.docx</url>
	</section>
</resume>
